Art and Architecture of Japan Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Art and Architecture of Japan Slide Collection
1960-2005
VRC 1700
Yale University Arts Library
24
113 boxes in 19 containers
Collection consists of color and black and white 35 mm slides of Japanese arts. Includes architecture, painting, sculpture, arms and armor, calligraphy, ceramics, enamels, furniture, lacquer, metalwork, and textiles.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of color and black and white 35 mm slides of Japanese arts. Includes architecture, painting, sculpture, arms and armor, calligraphy, ceramics, enamels, furniture, lacquer, metalwork, and textiles.
Arrangement
Arranged by medium. Further sub-divided by chronological period or location, and if known, by artist name.
Arts -- Japan; Arts, Japanese; Slides; Reproductions
- Painting (Box 1)
  - General [Slide box 1] (Box 1)
    - Various Titles (Box 1)
  - Prehistoric period, before 553 AD (Box 1)
    - Various Titles (Box 1)
  - Suiko period, 553-650 (Box 1)
    - Various Titles (Box 1)
  - Hakuho period, 650-710 (Box 1)
    - Various Titles (Box 1)
    - Takamatsu-zuka (Box 1)
    - Horyu-ji (Box 1)
      - Kondo Wall Paintings (Box 1)
  - Tempyo period, 710-794 (Box 1)
    - Ladies under trees screen [Slide boxes 1-2] (Box 1)
    - E Inga-kyo (Box 1)
  - Jogan period, 794-897 (Box 1)
    - Iconographic drawings (Box 1)
    - 12 Kings (Box 1)
    - Mandara (Box 1)
      - Shiki Mandara (Box 1)
      - Taishakuten Mandara (Box 1)
      - Kongokai Mandara (Box 1)
      - Taizokai Mandara (Box 1)
      - Takao Mandara (Box 1)
    - Portraits (Box 1)
  - Fujiwara Period, 898-1185 (Box 1)
    - Artist Unknown (Box 1)
      - Various Titles (Box 1)
      - Iconographic drawings (Box 1)
      - Albums [Slide box 3] (Box 1)
      - Doors (Box 1)
      - Handscrolls (Box 1)
        - Various Titles (Box 1)
        - Choju jimbutsu giga (Box 1)
        - Chuson-ji Kyo (Box 1)
        - Gaki Zoshi (Box 1)
        - Genji Monogatari (Box 1)
          - Cont. (from Kashiwagi) [Slide box 4] (Box 1)
        - Hatsuki Monogatari (Box 1)
        - Heike Nokyo (Box 1)
        - Jigoku Zoshi (Box 1)
        - Kokawadera Engi (Box 1)
        - Nezame Monogatari [Slide box 5] (Box 1)
        - Shigisan Engi Emaki (Box 1)
        - Yamai Zoshi [Slide box 6] (Box 1)
      - Hanging Scrolls (Box 1)
        - Various Titles (Box 1)
        - Arhats (Box 1)
          - Sixteen Arhats (Box 1)
        - Amida (Box 1)
          - Amida's Raigo (Box 1)
          - Amida Triad (Box 1)
        - Bosatsu Figures (Box 1)
          - Fugen (Box 1)
          - Fugen and Ten Rasetsunyo (Box 1)
          - Go-Dairiki (5 Great Bosatsu) (Box 1)
          - Juichimen Kannon (Box 1)
          - Kokuzo Bosatsu (Box 1)
          - Senju Kannon (Box 1)
        - Mandaras (Box 1)
        - Myo-o Figures [Slide boxes 6-7] (Box 1–2)
        - Portraits [Slide box 7] (Box 2)
        - Shaka (Box 2)
        - Twelve Kings (Deva) (Box 2)
      - Painted Rooms (Box 2)
        - Various Titles (Box 2)
      - Screens (Box 2)
        - Senzui Byobu (Box 2)
        - Shotoku Taishi Eden (Box 2)
      - Known Artists (Box 2)
        - Tokiwa Mitsunaga [Slide boxes 7-8] (Box 2)
        - Fujiwara Munehiro [Slide box 8] (Box 2)
          - Fujiwara Nobuzane, 1176-1265 (Box 2)
          - Takuma Tameto, ac. ca. 1132-1174 (Box 2)
  - Kamakura Period, 1185-13360 (Box 2)
    - Artist Unknown (Box 2)
      - Various Titles (Box 2)
      - Iconographic drawings (Box 2)
      - Fans (Box 2)
      - Handscrolls (Box 2)
        - Choju-jimbutsu giga: Scrolls 3 & 4 (Box 2)
        - E Inga-kyo (Box 2)
        - Eshi-no-soshi (Box 2)
        - Genji monogatari [Slide box 9] (Box 2)
        - Haseo kyo soshi (Box 2)
        - Heiji monogatari emaki [Slide boxes 9-10] (Box 2)
        - Honen Shonin eden [Slide box 10] (Box 2)
        - Ise monogatari (Box 2)
        - Ishiyamadera engi [Slide boxes 10-11] (Box 2)
        - Jidai Fudo Utaawase-e [Slide box 11] (Box 2)
        - Jigoku-zoshi emaki (Box 2)
        - Jin'o-ji engi emaki (Box 2)
        - Jizo bosatsu reigenki (Box 2)
        - Kegon engi (Box 2)
        - Kibi Daijin nitto [Slide boxes 11-12] (Box 2)
        - Kitano Tenjin engi [Slide box 12] (Box 2)
        - Komakurabe gyoko emaki (Box 2)
        - Makura no soshi [Slide box 12b] (Box 2)
          General
          Slide box 12b located in container 19
        - Murasaki Shikibu nikki (Box 2)
        - Pillow Book of Sei Shonagon (Box 2)
        - Saigyo monogatari (Box 2)
        - Shokunin utaawase (Box 2)
        - Taima mandara engi (Box 2)
        - 36 Poets (Agedatami version) (Box 2)
        - Takafusakyo Tsuyakotoba (Box 2)
        - Toyonoakari e-soshi (Box 2)
      - Hanging scrolls [Slide box 13] (Box 3)
        - Various Titles (Box 3)
        - 4 Guardian Kings (Box 3)
        - Kariteimo (Box 3)
        - Six Realms (Box 3)
        - Amida (Box 3)
          - Amida Coming Across Mountains (Box 3)
          - Haya Raigo (Box 3)
        - Bosatsu figures (Box 3)
          - Fugen and Ten Rasetsu-Nyo (Box 3)
          - Monju crossing sea (Box 3)
        - Daruma (Box 3)
        - Mandaras (Box 3)
          - Kumano mandara (Box 3)
          - Taima mandara (Box 3)
        - Myo-o Figures (Box 3)
        - Portraits [Slide box 14] (Box 3)
          - Various Titles (Box 3)
          - 36 Poets (Box 3)
        - Shaka (Box 3)
        - Twelve Kings (Box 3)
      - Screens (Box 3)
        - Various Titles (Box 3)
        - 16 Arhats screen (Nara, Horyu-ji) (Box 3)
        - Koya Senzui Byobu (Kyoto, Damoto Collection) (Box 3)
        - Senzui Byobu (Kyoto, Jingo-ji) (Box 3)
    - Known Artists (Box 3)
      - Takuma Choga, ac. 1253-1270 (Box 3)
      - Eiga, ca. 1310 (Box 3)
      - En-I, ac. 13th century [Slide boxes 14-15] (Box 3)
      - Minamoto Goshin [Slide box 15] (Box 3)
      - Joga (Box 3)
      - Jonin (Box 3)
      - Fujiwara Nobuzane [Slide boxes 15-16] (Box 3)
      - Rokurobe Rengyo, ac. 1298 [Slide box 16] (Box 3)
        - Tosei-den Emaki (Box 3)
      - Shinkai, ac. 1278-1287 (Box 3)
      - Shinken, 1179-1261 (Box 3)
      - Takuma Shoga, ac. ca. 1191 [Slide boxes 16-17] (Box 3)
      - Fujiwara Takanobu [Slide box 17] (Box 3)
      - Takashina Takakane, ac. 14th c. (Box 3)
  - Ashikaga Period, 1336-1573 (Box 3)
    - Artist Unknown (Box 3)
      - Books (Box 3)
      - Fans, Fan Albums, Fan Screens (Box 3)
        - Hiroshima (Box 3)
        - Kyoto (Box 3)
      - Handscrolls (Box 3)
        - Various Titles (Box 3)
        - Ashibiki (Box 3)
        - Benkei monogatari (Box 3)
        - Fujibukuro soshi (Box 3)
        - Genji monogatari (Box 3)
        - Hasedera engi emaki (Box 3)
        - Hongan-ji shonin (Box 3)
        - Ishiyamadera engi [Slide boxes 17-18] (Box 3)
        - Ise monogatari [Slide box 18] (Box 3)
        - Jingu kogo engi emaki (Box 3)
        - Ko Atsumori (Box 3)
        - Konda Sokyo engi emaki (Box 3)
        - Kondai-ji Yata Jizo engi emaki (Box 3)
        - Kumano no Honji (Box 3)
        - Matsukaze murasame (Box 3)
        - Mokuren rescues his mother (Box 3)
        - Nezumi no soshi (Box 3)
        - Oyo no Ama (Box 3)
        - Sanno Reigenke emaki (Box 3)
        - Saru no soshi (Box 3)
        - Shotoku Taishi eden (Box 3)
        - Soboku monogatari (Box 3)
        - Sugejin Godenki emaki (Box 3)
        - Tameyo no soshi (Box 3)
        - Tsukumogami soshi (Box 3)
        - Twelve Descriptions (Box 3)
        - Yashima Niko monogatari (Box 3)
        - Zen'e Shonin emaki (Box 3)
      - Hanging Scrolls (Box 3)
        - Various Titles (Box 3)
        - Daruma (Box 3)
        - Landscapes [Slide boxes 18-19] (Box 3)
        - Mandara [Slide box 19] (Box 4)
        - Portraits (Box 4)
        - Shaka (Box 4)
      - Screens (Box 4)
        - Various Titles (Box 4)
        - Bugaku Screens (Kyoto, Kitano Shrine) (Box 4)
        - Genre Paintings of Annual Events (Box 4)
        - Landscape of the Four Seasons (Box 4)
        - Pines by a seashore (Box 4)
        - Chiba (Box 4)
          - Various Titles (Box 4)
        - Tokyo (Box 4)
          - Various Titles (Box 4)
          - Rakuchu Rakugai [Slide box 20] (Box 4)
    - Artist Known (Box 4)
      - Bokkei, ac. ca. 15th century (Box 4)
      - Bokusai, d. 1492 (Box 4)
      - Bokusho Shusei, ca. 1394-ca. 1469 (Box 4)
      - Gyokuen Bompo, 1344-1420 (Box 4)
      - Bunsei, ac. 15th century (Box 4)
      - Tan'an Chiden, ac. 1504-1520 (Box 4)
      - Chuan Shinko, ac. ca. 1444-1457 (Box 4)
      - Yamada Doan, d. ca. 1573 (Box 4)
      - Tosa Eishun, ac. ca. 1369-1418 (Box 4)
      - Gakuo, ac. ca. 1500 (Box 4)
      - Shingei Geiami, 1431-1485 [Slide box 21] (Box 4)
      - Ue Gukei, ac. 1361-1375 (Box 4)
      - Kamonnosuke Hisakuni (Box 4)
      - Isshi (Box 4)
      - Rokaku Jakusai, ca. 1348-1424 (Box 4)
      - Soga Dasoku, d. ca. 1483 (Box 4)
      - Josetsu, ac. early 15th century (Box 4)
      - Kano Gyokuraku, ca. 1550-1590 (Box 4)
      - Kano Hideyori, d. 1557 (Box 4)
      - Kano Masanobu, 1434-1530 (Box 4)
      - Kano Motonobu, 1476-1559 [Slide boxes 21-23] (Box 4)
        - Various Titles (Box 4)
        - Hyogo [Slide box 22] (Box 4)
        - Tokyo (Box 4)
          - National Museum (Box 4)
          - Sairyo-ji (Box 4)
          - Reiun-in (Box 4)
          - Daisen-in (Box 4)
          - Tokaian (Box 4)
        - Kyoto [Slide box 23] (Box 4)
      - Kano Nagayoshi, ac. 16th century (Box 4)
      - Kano Yukinobu, 1513-1575 (Box 4)
      - Kantei, ac. 15th century (Box 4)
      - Kao, ac. 1300-1345 (Box 4)
      - Keiboku, ac. 16th century (Box 4)
      - Keisetsusai, ac. 16th century (Box 4)
      - Keison (Box 4)
      - Koetsu (Box 4)
      - Korehisa, ac. 14th century (Box 4)
      - Kichizan Mincho, 1352-1431 [Slide boxes 23-24] (Box 4)
      - Mokuan Reien, d. ca. 1348 [Slide box 24] (Box 4)
      - Shinno Noami, 1397-1471 (Box 4)
      - Gukyoku Reisai, ac. ca. 1435 (Box 4)
      - Ryozen, ac. 1328-1352 (Box 4)
      - Sekkyakushi (Box 4)
      - Senka, ac. 1520-1530 (Box 4)
      - Sesshu Toyo, 1420-1506 [Slide boxes 24-25] (Box 4–5)
      - Sesso, ac. 15th century [Slide box 25] (Box 5)
      - Sesson Shukei, 1504-1589 [Slide boxes 25-26] (Box 5)
      - Shikibu, ac. 16th century [Slide box 26] (Box 5)
      - Shikan (Box 5)
      - Shokei (Kenko Shokei) [Slide boxes 26-27] (Box 5)
      - Shokei Tan'yu, ac. 1440-1460 [Slide box 27] (Box 5)
      - Soga Shosen, ac. 16th century (Box 5)
      - Ri Shubun, ac. 1424 (Box 5)
      - Tensho Shubun, ac. 15th century (Box 5)
      - Shugetsu, d. ca. 1510 (Box 5)
      - Muto Shui, ac. ca. 1349 (Box 5)
      - Shuko, ac. 15th century (Box 5)
      - Shusei, ca. 1459 (Box 5)
      - Shusetsu Dojin, ac. 15th century (Box 5)
      - Soami, d. 1525 [Slide boxes 27-28] (Box 5)
      - Oguri Sokei, ac. 15th century [Slide box 28] (Box 5)
      - Oguri Soritsu, ac. 15th century (Box 5)
      - Oguri Sotan, 1413-1481 (Box 5)
      - Fujiwara Takaaki, d. 1351 (Box 5)
      - Fujiwara Takamasa, ac. 14th century (Box 5)
      - Awataguchi Takamitsu, ac. 15th century (Box 5)
      - Tesshu, d. 1366 (Box 5)
      - Tosa Hirokane, ca. 1439-1492 (Box 5)
      - Tosa Mitsukuni, ac. 1394-1427 (Box 5)
      - Tosa Mitsumochi, ca. 1490-1559 (Box 5)
      - Tosa Mitsumoto (Box 5)
      - Tosa Mitsunobu, 1430-1521 [Slide boxes 28-29] (Box 5)
      - Tosa Mitsushige (Box 5)
      - Tosa Yukihide, ac. ca. 1430 (Box 5)
      - Toshun, ac. 1506-1542 (Box 5)
      - Yogetsu, ac. ca. 1485 (Box 5)
      - Ashikaga Yoshimochi, 1386-1428 (Box 5)
      - Fujiwara Yukimitsu, ac. 1352-1389 (Box 5)
      - Zosan, ac. 16th century (Box 5)
  - Momoyama Period, 1573-1615 (Box 5)
    - Namban Art (Box 5)
      - Various Titles (Box 5)
      - 15 Mysteries of S. Mary (Box 5)
      - 28 Cities (Box 5)
      - Battle of Lepanto/ World Map (Murayama) (Box 5)
      - Equestrian Kings (Fujii) (Box 5)
      - Equestrian Kings (Kobe) [Slide box 30] (Box 5)
      - Europeans in Japan (Tokyo) (Box 5)
      - King and Courtiers (Boston) (Box 5)
      - Westerners in Japan (Collection Unknown) (Box 5)
      - Westerners Playing their Music (Atami) (Box 5)
      - Westerners Playing their Music (Ex-Kuroda) (Box 5)
      - Westerners Playing their Music (Tokyo) (Box 5)
      - World Map / 4 Cities (Kobe) (Box 5)
    - Artist Unknown (Box 5)
      - Albums/Books (Box 5)
      - Various (Box 5)
        - Ise monogatari (Box 5)
        - Iwaya no soshi (Box 5)
      - Fusuma (Sliding Doors) (Box 5)
      - Handscrolls (Box 5)
      - Hanging scrolls (Box 5)
      - Screens (Box 5)
        - Various Titles [Slide boxes 30-31] (Box 5)
        - Biography of Priest Saigyo [Slide box 31] (Box 6)
        - Genre scene at Onjo-ji and Hiei Shrine (Box 6)
        - Heiji monogatari (Box 6)
        - Horse trading (Kyoto, Daigoji) (Box 6)
        - Horse trading (Horses in stable) (Shiga, Taga Shrine) (Box 6)
        - Hogen monogatari (Box 6)
        - Merrymaking under cherry blossoms (Box 6)
        - Rakuchu Rakugai (Views in and around the Capital)[Slide boxes 31-32] (Box 6)
          - Burke Collection (Box 6)
          - Mitsui Collection (Box 6)
          - National Museum, Tokyo (Box 6)
          - Yabumoto Collection (Box 6)
          - Yamaoka Collection (Box 6)
          - Saigyo monogatari (Box 6)
          - Sanjusangendo archery meet (Box 6)
          - Sun and Moon landscape (Box 6)
          - Uji Bridge (Box 6)
    - Known Artists (Box 6)
      - Soga Chokuan, d. 1610 (Box 6)
      - Hasegawa Kyuzo, 1568-1593 (Box 6)
      - Hasegawa Tohaku, 1539-1610 [Slide boxes 32, 33, & 34] (Box 6)
      - Honami Koetsu, 1558-1637 [Slide box 34] (Box 6)
      - Kaiho Yusho, 1533-1615 (Box 6)
      - Kano Eitoku, 1543-1590 [Slide boxes 34-35] (Box 6)
      - Kano Mitsunobu, 1565-1608 [Slide box 35] (Box 6)
      - Kano Naganobu, 1577-1654 (Box 6)
      - Kano Naizen, 1570-1616 (Box 6)
      - Kano Sadanobu, 1597-1623 (Box 6)
      - Kano Sanraku, 1559-1635 [Slide boxes 36-37] (Box 6–7)
      - Kano Shoei, 1519-1592 [Slide box 37] (Box 7)
      - Kano Soshu, 1551-1601 (Box 7)
      - Kano Takanobu, 1571-1618 [Slide boxes 37-38] (Box 7)
      - Kano Yoshinobu, 1582-1640 [Slide box 38] (Box 7)
      - Nobukata Hyogo (Box 7)
      - Shokado, 1584-1639 (Box 7)
      - Tawaraya Sotatsu, 1576-1643 [Slide boxes 38-39] (Box 7)
      - Sotatsu, School of [Slide box 40] (Box 7)
      - Tosa Mitsuyoshi, 1539-1613 (Box 7)
      - Unkoku Togan, 1547-1618 [Slide boxes 40-41] (Box 7)
  - Tokugawa Period, 1615-1867 (Box 7)
    [Slide box 41]
    - Artist Unknown [Slide boxes 41-42] (Box 7)
      - Hanging scrolls [Slide box 42] (Box 7)
      - Screens (Box 7)
        - Various (Box 7)
        - Amusements at Shijo (Box 7)
        - Cherry Blossom Viewing (Box 7)
        - Dancers (Box 7)
        - Drawings of Hokoku Sairei-zu (Box 7)
        - Drying Fishnets [Slide box 43] (Box 8)
        - Entertainment at the House (Box 8)
        - Fields of Musashino (Box 8)
        - Flower viewing pleasures (Box 8)
        - Gay quarters of Kyoto (Box 8)
        - Gion festival (Box 8)
        - Heike monogatari (Box 8)
        - Hikone byobu (Box 8)
        - Honda Heihachiro (Box 8)
        - Indoor Pleasures (Box 8)
        - Kabuki and Outdoor enjoyments (Box 8)
        - Kamo Horse Race (Box 8)
        - Nagasaki Screen (Box 8)
        - Noh and Kyogen Players (Box 8)
        - Poem papers on blossoming plum (Box 8)
        - Rakuchu rakugai (Box 8)
          - Various collections [Slide boxes 43-44] (Box 8)
          - Honda Collection [Slide box 44] (Box 8)
          - Hayashi Collection (Box 8)
          - Kobe (Box 8)
          - New York (Box 8)
          - Okayama (Box 8)
          - Osaka (Box 8)
          - Tokyo (Box 8)
        - Sarutori byobu (Box 8)
        - Summer Battle of Osaka Castle (Box 8)
        - Tagasode (Box 8)
        - Tale of Genji (YUAG) (Box 8)
        - Uji Bridge (Box 8)
        - Water wheels (Box 8)
        - Willow bridge and water wheels (Box 8)
        - Women's Pleasures/Women's Genre [Slide boxes 44-45] (Box 8)
      - Wall painting [Slide box 45] (Box 8)
      - Albums (Box 8)
      - Handscrolls (Box 8)
        - Various Titles (Box 8)
    - Known Artists (Box 8)
      - Aoki Mokubei, 1767-1833 (Box 8)
      - Araki Jogen, ca. 1773-1824 (Box 8)
      - Basho Matsuo, 1644-1694 (Box 8)
      - Fukae roshu, 1699-1757 (Box 8)
      - Fujimoto Tesseki, 1817-1863 (Box 8)
      - Furuyama Moromasa, ac. 18th century (Box 8)
      - Gibon Sengai, 1751-1837 (Box 8)
      - Gion Nankai, 1677-1751 (Box 8)
      - Hanabusa Itcho, 1652-1724 (Box 8)
      - Hakuen (Box 8)
      - Hakuin, 1685-1768 [Slide boxes 45-46] (Box 8)
      - Hanegawa Toei [Slide box 46] (Box 8)
      - Hasegawa Toin, ac. ca. 1620 (Box 8)
      - Hasegawa Sakon, ac. early 17th century (Box 8)
      - Hasegawa Sekko, ac. early 17th century (Box 8)
      - Hasegawa Totetsu, ac. 1675 (Box 8)
      - Hiroshige Ando, 1797-1858 (Box 8)
      - Hishikawa Moronobu, 1618-1694 (Box 8)
      - Hirowatari Koshu, 1737-1784 (Box 8)
      - Hokusai, 1760-1849 (Box 8)
      - Ichu (Box 8)
      - Ikeno Gyokuran, 1728-1784 (Box 8)
      - Ikeno Taiga, 1723-1776 [Slide boxes 46-47] (Box 8)
      - Ishizaki Yushi, 1768-1846 [Slide box 47] (Box 8)
      - Ito Jakuchu, 1713-1800 (Box 8)
      - Itsunen Shoyu, 1601-1668 (Box 8)
      - Itsuun Kinoshita (Box 8)
      - Iwasa Matabei, 1578-1650 [Slide boxes 47-48] (Box 8)
      - Sagyoku Katsu [Slide box 48] (Box 8)
      - Kaigetsudo Ando, ac. 1st half 18th century (Box 8)
      - Kaigetsudo Doshin, ac. 1700-1716 (Box 8)
      - Kaiho Yusetsu, 1598-1677 (Box 8)
      - Kano Eikei (Box 8)
      - Kano Eino (Box 8)
      - Kano Jinnojo, ca. 1595-1648 (Box 8)
      - Kano Koi, ca. 1569-1636 [Slide boxes 48-49] (Box 8–9)
      - Kano Naonobu, 1607-1650 [Slide box 49] (Box 9)
      - Kano Osanobu (Box 9)
      - Kano Sanboku (Box 9)
      - Kano Sansetsu, 1589-1651 (Box 9)
      - Kano Shigenobu, mid 17th century (Box 9)
      - Kano Tanyu, 1602-1674 [Slide boxes 49-50] (Box 9)
      - Kano Tsunenobu, 1636-1713 [Slide box 51] (Box 9)
      - Kano Ujinobu, 1616-1669 (Box 9)
      - Kano Yosen'in, 1753-1808 (Box 9)
      - Ike Kanryo, 1753-1830 (Box 9)
      - Kameda Bosai, 1752-1826 (Box 9)
      - Katayama Yokoku, 1762-1803 (Box 9)
      - Katsukawa Shunsho, 1726-1792 (Box 9)
      - Kawanabe Gyosai, 1831-1889 (Box 9)
      - Ki Baitei, 1734-1810 (Box 9)
      - Kimura Kenkado, 1736-1802 (Box 9)
      - Kitagawa Kikumaro, d. 1830 (Box 9)
      - Kitagawa Sosetsu, ac. mid 17th century (Box 9)
      - Ko Fuyo, 1722-1784 (Box 9)
      - Komai Genki, 1747-1797 (Box 9)
      - Kuwayama Gyokushu, 1737-1812 (Box 9)
      - Kuzumi Morikage, d. ca. 1700 (Box 9)
      - Maruyama Okyo, 1733-1795 [Slide boxes 51-52] (Box 9)
      - Maruyama Ozui, 1766-1829 [Slide box 52] (Box 9)
      - Matsumura Goshun, 1752-1811 (Box 9)
      - Miyagawa Choshun, 1683-1753 (Box 9)
      - Miyamoto Musashi, 1584-1645 (Box 9)
      - Momota Hyuei (Box 9)
      - Mori Sosen (Box 9)
      - Nagasawa Rosetsu, 1755-1799 [Slide boxes 52-53] (Box 9)
      - Nakabayashi Chikkei, 1816-1867 [Slide box 53] (Box 9)
      - Nakabayashi Chikuto, 1766-1853 (Box 9)
      - Nakamura Hochu, ac. 1793-1813 (Box 9)
      - Nakayama Koyo, 1717-1780 (Box 9)
      - Nonoguchi Ryuho, 1595-1669 (Box 9)
      - Noro Kaiseki, 1747-1828 (Box 9)
      - Nukina Kaioku, 1778-1863 (Box 9)
      - Odano Naotake, 1749-1780 (Box 9)
      - Ogata Kenzan, 1663-1743 (Box 9)
      - Ogata Korin, 1663-1716 [Slide boxes 53-54] (Box 9)
      - Okada Beisanjin, 1744-1818 [Slide box 54] (Box 9)
      - Okada Hanko, 1782-1846 (Box 9)
      - Okamoto Shuki, 1782-1846 [Slide box 55] (Box 10)
      - Okamoto Shuki, 1785-1862 (Box 10)
      - Okumura Masanobu, 1690-1768 (Box 10)
      - Ono no Otsu, 1568-1631 (Box 10)
      - Rai San'yo, 1780-1832 (Box 10)
      - Sakai Hoitsu, 1761-1828 (Box 10)
      - Arisaka Hokuba, 1771-1844 (Box 10)
      - Katsushika Hokusai, 1760-1849 (Box 10)
      - Sasaki Hyakusen, 1698-1753 (Box 10)
      - Sakuma Sakyo, 1581-1657 (Box 10)
      - Satake Shozan, 1748-1785 (Box 10)
      - Shiba Kokan, 1747-1818 (Box 10)
      - Shibata Zeshin, 1807-1891 (Box 10)
      - Shiokawa Bunrin, 1808-1877 (Box 10)
      - Shokado Shojo, 1584-1639 (Box 10)
      - Soga Nichokuan, ac. mid. 17th century (Box 10)
      - Soga Shohaku, d. 1781 [Slide boxes 55-56] (Box 10)
      - Sotatsu, School of [Slide box 56] (Box 10)
      - Sumiyoshi Gukei, 1631-1705 (Box 10)
      - Sumiyoshi Hiromori, 1705-1777 (Box 10)
      - Sumiyoshi Jokei, 1599-1670 (Box 10)
      - Suzuki Kiitsu, 1796-1858 (Box 10)
      - Taiho, Obaku (Box 10)
      - Takahashi Sohei, 1804-1834 (Box 10)
      - Takeda Harunobu, ac. 18th century (Box 10)
      - Taki Katei, 1830-1901 (Box 10)
      - Tani Buncho, 1764-1840 (Box 10)
      - Tanomura Chikuden, 1777-1835 [Slide box 57] (Box 10)
      - Tatebayashi Kagei, ac. 18th century (Box 10)
      - Tawaraya Sosetsu, ac. 1639-1650 (Box 10)
      - Tosa Mitsunori, 1583-1638 [Slide boxes 57-58] (Box 10)
      - Tosa Mitsuoki, 1617-1691 [Slide box 58] (Box 10)
      - Tosa Mitsumoto (Box 10)
      - Tsubaki Chinzan, 1801-1854 (Box 10)
      - Ukita Ikkei, 1795-1859 (Box 10)
      - Unkoku Toeki, 1591-1644 (Box 10)
      - Uragami Gyokudo, 1745-1821 [Slide boxes 58-59] (Box 10)
      - Uragami Shunkin, 1779-1846 [Slide box 59] (Box 10)
      - Watanabe Kazan, 1793-1841 (Box 10)
      - Watanabe Nangaku, 1767-1813 (Box 10)
      - Watanabe Ryokei, ac. ca. 1645 (Box 10)
      - Watanabe Shiko, 1683-1755 (Box 10)
      - Yamaguchi Sekkei, 1644-1732 (Box 10)
      - Yamamoto Soken, ac. 1683-1706 [Slide boxes 59-60] (Box 10)
      - Yanagisawa Kien, 1706-1758 [Slide box 60] (Box 10)
      - Yokoi Kinkoku, ac. 18th century (Box 10)
      - Yamamoto Baiitsu, 1783-1856 (Box 10)
      - Yosa Buson, 1716-1783 [Slide box 60-61] (Box 10)
- Prints (Box 10)
  [Slide box 61]
  - Artist Unknown (Box 10)
    - Various Titles (Box 10)
    - Nagasaki Prints (Box 10)
    - Saga-bon (Box 10)
  - Known Artists (Box 10)
    - Kaigetsudo Anchi, ac. 1700-1716 (Box 10)
    - Aodo Denzen, 1748-1822 (Box 10)
    - Shusaku Arakawa, 1936- (Box 10)
    - Ippitsusai Buncho, ac. 1765-1792 (Box 10)
    - Hanekawa Chincho, 1679-1754 (Box 10)
    - Eishosai Choki, ac. 1785-1805 (Box 10)
    - Kaigtesudo dohan, ac. 1700-1716 (Box 10)
    - Shikyusai Eiri, ac. 1789-1803 (Box 10)
    - Keisai Eisen, 1790-1848 (Box 10)
    - Chobunsai Eishi, 1756-1829 (Box 10)
    - Enkyo (Kabukido), 1749-1808 (Box 10)
    - Hashiguchi Goyo, 1881-1921 (Box 10)
    - Suzuki Harunobu, 1725-1770 [Slide boxes 61-62] (Box 10–11)
    - Kawase Hasui, 1883-1957 [Slide box 62] (Box 11)
    - Yoshida Hiroshi, 1876-1950 (Box 11)
    - Ando Hiroshige, 1797-1858 (Box 11)
      - Various Titles (Box 11)
      - 53 Stages of Tokaido [Slide boxes 62-63] (Box 11)
      - 69 Stations of Kisokaido [Slide box 63] (Box 11)
      - 100 Views of Edo (Box 11)
      - 8 Views of Tokyo (Box 11)
    - Hokkei, 1780-1850 (Box 11)
    - Shotei Hokuju (Box 11)
    - Katsushika Hokusai, 1760-1849 (Box 11)
      - Various Titles (Box 11)
      - Manga Sketches (Box 11)
      - 36 Views of Mount Fuji (Box 11)
    - Sugimura Jihei, ac. 1680-1698 [Slide box 64] (Box 11)
    - Yoshikawa Kampo, b. 1894 (Box 11)
    - Kawahara Keiga, ca. 1890 (Box 11)
    - Kondo Kihoyama, ac. 1704-1720 (Box 11)
    - Kobayashi Kiyochika, 1847-1915 (Box 11)
    - Torii Kiyohiro, ac. 1751-1765 (Box 11)
    - Torii Kiyomasu I, ac. 1696-1716 (Box 11)
    - Torii Kiyomasu II, 1706-1763 [Slide box 65] (Box 11)
    - Torii Kiyomitsu, 1735-1785 (Box 11)
    - Torii Kiyonaga, 1752-1815 (Box 11)
    - Torii Kiyonobu I, 1664-1729 (Box 11)
    - Torii Kiyonobu II, 1702-1752 (Box 11)